# DAN MARICHAL FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

### **Contact**

danilo.marichal@icloud.com

• http://www.dynamodeveloper.com

**(**561) 420-5248

0

Greater New York City Area

in www.linkedin.com/in/danilomarichal-36b714112/

http://www.github.com/danilomarichal

### **Summary**

Having a background in the arts and refined management skills, I'm able to merge creativity and discipline with coding. My previous education and experiences enable me to acknowledge business core values and prioritize specific tasks, but also to emphasize aesthetics and visual design at the same time.

### **Skills**

Technical Skills
HTML/CSS/JavaScript
JQuery
Node/Express.js
PSQL/MongoDB
Git/Github
Ruby on Rails
React/Angular
Ajax/JSON

Personal Skills
Analytical
Adaptability
Communication
Self-motivation
Leadership

Spanish English

Heroku

## **Projects**

Far-Fall Ville Game

Feb 2017 to Feb 2017

https://github.com/danilomarichal/Far-Fall-Ville/tree/master/clickGame Front end hidden elements game. HTML, CSS, JavasCript, JQuery.

Postrip Mar 2017 to Mar 2017

https://github.com/danilomarichal/postrip

Node/Express.js app that allows users to post pictures and share travel experiences. Front-end uses HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jquery and an Ajax call to integrate a real-time news from National Geographic's API. PSQL as database and utilize packages: Multer (image uploader), Bcrypt Salt (passwords/security), Express-session, Mustache-express.

What's Going On

Apr 2017 to Apr 2017

https://github.com/danilomarichal/project3/tree/master/wdi\_project\_3

Group project. Section Donate. Ruby on Rails app (Section Donate) helps users to find non-profit organizations and make donations. It uses Bootstrap to style, PSQL database and gems like HTTParty to integrate a third party API.

Finadvisor May 2017 to May 2017

https://github.com/danilomarichal/finacial\_advisor

App that helps users to calculate expenses, mortgage rates and find their best investment profile. Built on Express.js, Utilizes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jquery and Ajax to integrate API. PSQL as database and utilize packages: Bcrypt Salt (passwords/security), Express-session, Mustache-express.

# **Employment**

Prevalent Inc.

Warren, NJ

Data Transfer Specialist (Consultant)

Aug 2017 to Current

Analysis, review and data transfer of vendor risk assessment forms.

Wealth Health llc
Web Developer (Consultant)

Roseland, NJ Jul 2017 to Aug 2017

Worked on improvement of functionality and responsiveness of company's website.

General Assembly (WDI) Full Stack Web Developer New York, NY Jan 2017 to May 2017

Web Development Immersive (WDI) is a training program dedicated to prepare students to think like engineers and approach problems creatively in order to build the next generation of web applications

and digital products.

Various Europe/USA Management/Operations Sep 2006 to Dec 2016

10 Years of work experience in the Food/Travel/Hospitality industries in Europe and the US; monitoring and reporting financial information, evaluating and auditing operations in order to improve productivity and quality, supervising customer service/satisfaction, hiring/training staff, ensuring companies' compliance policies.

# **Education**

International University of Arts of Havana Bachelor of Arts. Dramatic Arts 2006

General Assembly NYC Certification Web Development 2017